<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Azar Mamiyev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Azar Mamiyev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 01:51:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some stuff that you need to know before learning DevOps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/prerequisites-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 01:51:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/prerequisites-devops/</guid>
      <description>This blog contains the notes that I took while I was watching the freeCodeCamp video about DevOps prerequisites. By reading this blog you can get fundamental knowledge about the things you need to know before learning DevOps. I mostly focused on keywords and some small description about them, but you can research more about those by yourself to build long lasting knowledge.
You can also check the video yourself by clicking here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting Encryption and Decryption with Python: Understanding the Transposition Cipher</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/transposition_cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:07:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/transposition_cipher/</guid>
      <description>In the world of data security, encryption is like a fortress protecting sensitive information from prying eyes. Among the many encryption methods, there&amp;rsquo;s one called the Transposition Cipher. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like rearranging the letters of a word to make it look scrambled. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at how this encryption method works using a Python script, you can find full project here.
Understanding the Code Let&amp;rsquo;s break down the code step by step:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 22:19:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that you visited my blog! I&amp;rsquo;m so glad you&amp;rsquo;re here. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share my thoughts with you on all things related to Software Development, Cybersecurity, Internet privacy, and AI.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
